So that information, that lie came from
Israel.
>> Yes.
>> Right. Why would a president believe a
foreign intel agency before his own?
>> Especially when you know that the
Israelis have a vested interest in you
doing their dirty work for them. We're
we're doing Israel's bidding for it.
>> So why would you as a practical matter
need to consult other countries? Because
there is this sense like as an
exceptional nation, we don't need
anyone's permission to act.
Israel hijacked US foreign policy.
That's what Tucker Carlson and John
Kiryaku both are aligning on here in
this clip. Kiraaku being the famous
former CIA officer that heroically blew
the cover off the CIA's unconstitutional
and immoral torture program and spent
time in prison for it. The two discuss
the current war in Iran, Trump's
actions, and what really lays bare the
idea that it's the Israelis, the
so-called vassel country of the United
States, that exert much more influence
in our political system than vice versa.
Let's see them break it down here.
Please like the video and subscribe to
the channel. The president said, well,
two things. One, that we destroyed
Iran's nuclear program in June.
>> Mhm. And but you're saying that it
>> that there was no nuclear program.
>> There was no nuclear program. They had
partially uh enriched uranium certainly
which under the NPT they're allowed to
do. It's it's subject to United Nations
inspection. Um yeah they were not
>> but there was no nuclear program in in
June.
>> No nuclear weapons program.
>> So nuclear weapons program right. So we
destroyed the nuclear weapons program
which doesn't exist. But then in
February, we were told again that the
nuclear weapons program is absolutely
real, that the threat is imminent.
>> Yes.
>> People go on television on Fox News and
say Iran can lob an ICBM into Miami and
obliterate the United States.
>> You know, I'm glad that you brought that
up, too, because that is also not true.
And a lot of people a lot of people are
saying it. The Iranians did something
recently that was that was interesting
in that they took they took two of their
medium-range missiles. They stripped
them down to the point where it was just
the missile and the engine and that was
it. There was nothing inside of them
just to see how much distance they could
get and they made it almost to Diego
Garcia which is far. So if you instead
point them toward Europe, yes, without
anything inside these these missiles,
they could reach Western Europe. That's
not a delivery system. That's just smoke
and mirrors. They can only go that far
if they're completely empty. If you
weigh them down with explosives or, god
forbid, with, you know, nuclear
material, even if it's just to make a
dirty bomb, they can't get that far.
They could get to Cyprus.
They could get certainly to Israel and
easily to the the Arab Gulf countries,
but there was no threat to the United
States.
>> So, not at all. And that's exactly
right. This whole case for war was built
up on propaganda. And that's exactly
what the notion that, hey, a mushroom
cloud would suddenly appear from Iran
above Chicago or New York or Miami. It
It's just so preposterous. It was never
wellounded. It's been so thoroughly
exposed. And everything that is drummed
up to concoct that looks more and more
ridiculous. In hindsight, it looks much
more ridiculous than the idea that Iraq
had weapons of mass destruction. because
during the 80s, we know it did because
the United States provided it to Iraq to
fight a war against Iran in the 1980s.
But this is just a mountain of lies to
support this war. This idea that they
were on the verge of a nuclear weapon.
None of the intelligence agencies within
the United States would even say that.
And those are the institutions most
vested with the idea of wanting to start
foreign wars. That's what the CIA has
done from the jump. From Cuba and
Guatemala and overthrowing the Iranian
regime in 1953, all the propaganda and
psychological operation waged against
the American people to support the war
on terror. It's been the CIA and the NSA
that has drummed up these wars. But they
didn't hold to the insane notion that
Iran had a nuclear weapon because it
never did. It's all preposterous
propaganda spread by the Israelis to
start this war that they've wanted for
three decades.
>> So the IC, the American intel community,
the those 18 agencies you referred to,
did anybody in those agencies say to the
president this is a major threat, the
nuclear program in Iran?
>> The people that I still talk to at the
agency say specifically, no.
>> No.
>> So that information, that lie came from
Israel.
>> Yes.
>> Right. Why would a president believe a
foreign intel agency before his own?
>> I don't know. That's really the $64,000
question. You you recall in the in the
first term when President uh Trump met
with uh Vladimir Putin. He did not take
his intelligence people into the meeting
with him. Putin took his intelligence
people into meeting with him because the
president said he trusted the other
side's intelligence people more than he
trusted his own. And I I get it. I get
that he believes that he was under
direct threat from, you know, the deep
state and the John Brennan's of the
world. I understand that. But um
I'm surprised that that feeling, that
belief has held over all this way into
the second term where you would believe
the Israeli information before you would
believe your own people's information.
especially when you know that the
Israelis have a vested interest in you
doing their dirty work for them.
>> A lot of us uh have been trying to
figure out how we got into this war with
Iran. I think the reporting is clear at
this point that there was really nobody
at the White House or in the American
intelligence community who was telling
the president, "Yeah, this is going to
be really easy."
>> Right.
>> But he came to that conclusion anyway.
There's a lot of speculation as to as to
why, but tell us about the process.
You're the president. You're trying to
figure out what's going to happen if you
declare war on this country.
>> How do you how do you find that
information? Where does that come from?
>> Well, I can tell you how President
George HW Bush did it and how President
George W. Bush did it. It's it's a
process. You have to
>> formal
>> formal process. You have to commission
um estimates from the intelligence
community. You you commission
intelligence, finished intelligence
reports from the CIA's directorate of
intelligence. You get an idea of what
the State Department is thinking about
it. You're talking to your secretaries
of state and defense, the national
security adviser. But then, and I think
this is even as important, you need to
talk to your friends and allies. You
need to know what the what the European
countries are saying or seeing. And then
our Gulf allies, the
>> Yeah. i.e. not Israel. Gulf allies do
not include the country pulling us into
endless conflicts in multiple theaters.
Syria, Libya, Iraq, Somalia, now Iran. I
prefer not to have entangling alliances
at all. I'm with Thomas Jefferson on
that. But Israel is not the ally that
works to the benefit of the American
people. Quite to the contrary. But yeah,
he's right. This actually was a process
in American history, believe it or not,
and much more so before Bush. But we're
even speaking relative terms here where
this time we woke up to this realization
that we had launched the next Israel
first war against Iran. It was just out
of not nowhere there was was the
groundwork laid. But Congress wasn't
involved. None of the intelligence
services in the United States supported
this. They didn't unleash a a scot
propaganda campaign for the most part in
comparison to Mossad and the Israelis.
at least if you trust bits and pieces
from that New York Times article, which
is always hard to do regarding the
Times. But I think a lot of that is for
damage control to say, "Hey, none of
Trump's cabinet members wanted this war
that's going horribly to absolve them of
kind of some of the negative
ramifications and negative reputational
damage that comes from this war. But at
the same time, there wasn't large forces
within the United States intelligence
communities. again, the ones that
generally wanted to involve us in all
these foreign wars in this case in terms
of a smoking gun. And Kuriyaku is right.
The deep state was trying to undermine
Trump in the first term. That's just
incontroversial. That's exactly what
happened. That's what Russia gate was.
It was a scam to say while Trump was
arming the Ukrainians and setting the
stage for increased hostilities in
Eastern Europe under the NATO wing,
which is the European wing of the
American military-industrial complex and
the US Empire, I should say. He was
being undermined by his own officials.
his own officials, many of them were
holdovers, from Obama, trying to frame
him for treason as he was acting bellos
toward Russia, pulling out of the INF,
providing $400 million in weaponry to
Ukraine that even Obama didn't give
after Obama helped overthrow the
Anakovich government in 2014.
But while this was happening, it served
as a smoke screen for what was really
happening. It wasn't Russia Gate, it was
Israel gate. It was Trump colluding with
Netanyahu to lay the groundwork for this
war. Even back in the first term, he
moved the US embassy to Jerusalem at the
behest of Israel. He signed the Abraham
Accords at the behest of Israel. Ripped
up the JCPOA
at the behest of Israel. Assassinated
Casam Solommani at the behest of Israel.
All this shows that Israel gate was
actually playing out, not Russia gate at
that time. Arab allies, we we really
needed to engage with all of them. and
then there's going to be a consensus at
some point at least among most of those
countries and then you come up with a
policy. I think that that's not what
took place in this case.
As as you know, you've heard the same
criticisms that I've heard in the Gulf.
The complaints are that they were not
consulted as allies. They were just sort
of brought along. And I was in Europe a
couple of weeks ago and a couple of
weeks before that and I heard the same
complaints that they weren't consulted.
The only apparent consultation that was
taking place was with the Israelis and
the Israelis really really wanted this
to get done. So why would you as a
practical matter need to consult other
countries cuz there is this sense like
as an exceptional nation we don't need
anyone's permission to act. Um, but
again, not as an ideological matter or a
matter of politeness or good form, but
as a practical matter before launching a
war. Why do you need to talk to the
Europeans in the Gulf States?
>> At the very least, you're going to want
political cover. You're also going to
want to give them an opportunity to come
up with plan B for their, let's say, oil
or gas needs or transportation issues.
You don't want them to be taken by
surprise because they're going to resent
you in the end.
>> And uh and we didn't do that. And they
resent us. I'll give you an example.
>> Yeah, absolutely. They resent us. How
can't they? And guess who else resents
the criminal US government? It's
American citizens paying more at the
pump right now because of this global
energy crisis unleashed as a direct
result of this war. The closure of the
straight of Hormuz doesn't seem like
it's going to be open through military
force. Trump can't do that. None of the
sham negotiators can do that. You think
that they'll be willing to dismantle
their ballistic missiles and reopen the
straight of Hormuz there. There's no
there's no reason to suggest that they
are going to do that. And the Europeans
are suffering too. Now, I don't exactly
care about the Europeans as much, but I
do care about maintaining close trade
relations with them, close diplomatic
relations, just as I do close trade and
diplomatic relations with Iran. By the
way, with Russia, by the way, with
China, by the way, with all countries,
use the military to protect the homeland
for once. That's what's never done. The
military is used for empire building in
Israel and the United States. That's
what we exist to do with the parasitical
Israel lobby preying on us, praying on
our treasury, being entitled to it, and
imposing inflation and debt on Americans
as a result. Now, let's take a moment to
thank our sponsor, Monetary Metals.
monetaryheyenmetals.com/vault
because lovers of liberty and sound
money already know why gold matters.
It's preserved purchasing power over
thousands of years while governments
debase paper currency. It's a hedge
against inflation. But despite this,
most people think of gold as something
that just sits around and you forget
about. But that just means it does
nothing for you. It doesn't earn a
yield. But that's where Monetary Metals
steps in. They've created a system where
you can earn yield on your gold paid in
more gold and in fact depending on the
opportunity up to 4%. So monetary metals
gives gold owners a way to guard against
inflation, earn a return and put their
metal into productive use instead of
relying on the fiat financial system, a
corrupt one at that. So if you already
own gold or are thinking of owning some,
this is well worth looking into. Go to
monetaryheyenmetals.com/vault
to learn how you can start earning a
return on your gold. Monetary Metals has
my full enthusiastic endorsement because
it's the ultimate way to protect
yourself from the corrupt financial
system. Now, let's get back into the
conversation.
I was in Ireland two weeks ago and uh at
the hotel they told me I was probably
going to have to leave extra early for
the airport because they were expecting
the largest demonstration in Irish
history which took place the next
morning and it was all because of home
heating oil prices and gasoline prices.
We didn't consult with the Irish or the
British or anybody else before launching
this thing. They were already having
problems because of the cut off of home
heating oil coming from Russia because
of the Ukraine war and then this was
just doubly difficult for them. And so
gas was we figured it out. Gas was $125
a gallon.
>> I mean if you don't have an electric
gasoline $125 a gallon and home heating
oil was astronomical to the point where
people were just you know freezing and
they're blaming us for it. So you want
to be able to consult our friends and
allies so that they have a chance to
come up with a plan to make the hurt on
their own people a little bit less
severe.
Um
Ireland is an enemy of Israel's the
prime minister and many cabinet
ministers in Israel have said that they
hate Ireland, they hate Europe, they
hate Europeans. So, do you think that
the president's um reluctance or failure
to bring them into this conversation
reflects Israel's priorities?
>> I hate to say it, but I I do actually. I
think that the Israelis
Look, I understand what a close friend
and ally Israel is and always has been.
I get it. But I feel like sometimes we
act in Israel's best interests rather
than in our own best interests. I think
this is one of those cases. The
Israelis, of course, are going to jump
up and down and yell about the Irish and
the Spanish and the Italians,
>> right?
>> But we should, you know, let them vent
and then do what's in the best interest
of the United States. And I feel like
we're not really doing that. group.
>> Yeah, I haven't done that in a long
time. I will push back a little bit. I
don't think that Israel is the ally of
the United States. At least when it
comes to the traditional definition of
ally, that one that has your back
actually serves to be a link that is
beneficial to you, not something that
Israel has done. Instead, Israel's acted
as a parasite. They've been the biggest
foreign policy recipient. $350 billion
dollars drawn the US into endless wars
again in multiple countries in that
region. All with the commonalities of
they happened to be adversaries of
Israel at that time including the most
preposterous Iraq when you sent a third
of a trillion forces or I'm sorry a
third of a million forces in the war on
terror to remove Saddam. And we didn't
exactly get a lot of benefit from that.
We got a lot of dead service members, a
ton of debt, 10 trillion in the war on
terror, and then you're funding al-Qaeda
for the sake of Israel in Syria to
depose Assad. That's what the US did.
It's criminal. And Israel has killed
more people than the Iranians in terms
of the USS Liberty attack in 1967.
Something that they never want to talk
about either. clearly flying the flag of
the United States in the context of that
war, the 1967 war. Israel bombed the USS
Liberty. Phil Turney will tell you all
about it right now. They are not allies.
They are super villains preying on our
livelihood, taking our wealth, seizing
our treasury for their territorial
ambitions. And our political elites are
totally complicit with it on both sides.
Trump most extreme in my lifetime, but
certainly presidents of all stripes.
>> We're doing Israel's bidding for it.
>> Have you seen this before? You you said
it's been a close relationship. You were
for many many years. That's true. Since
the formation of the country, really,
1948,
and there's always been pressure to help
Israel go along with its priorities. But
have you seen other instances when you
served in government where the United
States government
put Israel's interests above those of
the United States?
>> No. In fact, in fact, to the contrary,
in the Gulf War, the 199091 Gulf War,
and again in the Iraq war from 2003
onward, we specifically made decisions
that were in the best interest of the
United States to the point where the
Israelis complained viciferously to us
that they wanted us to do A and instead
we did B because B was better for the
United States.
>> All right, so this I disagree with a
little bit. in the Gulf War and in the
war in Iraq, the Iraq War II, so to
speak, Israel supported both wars. Now,
they might have wanted to have different
strategic objectives, but we know in
Iraq War II, Netanyahu came to the
United States in September of 2002 and
lobbyed Congress to depose Saddam. He
said that positive reverberations would
break out among the region. And Ariel
Chiron was the prime minister at that
time. He was behind it, too. He did want
to take out Iran first. That is well
documented as the United States is doing
right now or trying to do. Not exactly
very successful in that and there's no
sign that there will be a regime change.
They've removed from the table the idea
of regime change by doing an
assassination strike on Supreme Leader
Ali Ham. But Israel did support the Gulf
War in 91 and in the Iraq war. So on
that I don't think Kiryaku is right. And
I really admire Kiryaku.
>> And you know we would say well you know
that's that's foreign policy. You have
your interests, we have our interests.
There's no such thing as permanent
friends. There is such a thing as
permanent interests. This is our
interest and this is what we're going to
do. And that's just not it doesn't seem
to be the case today. I I don't
understand
how attacking Iran was in US national
interests. I I fully understand how this
was in Israel's interest. And the
Israelis have long wanted us to attack
Iran and to overthrow the uh the regime
in Tehran. I get that it's in their
interests. But I've never believed I
don't think any CIA officer, past or
present, believes or has believed that
the Iranians were anywhere near a
nuclear uh weapon. They don't have a
delivery system that could deliver a
nuclear weapon to the United States. And
um you know when you've got two national
intelligence estimates,
a national intelligence estimate is a
sense of the entire intelligence
community, all 18 organizations within
the US intelligence community
unanimously concluding that there is no
Iranian nuclear weapons program twice as
well as the late
>> there's no program.
>> No program.
No. Ayat Kamay issued a fatwa in 2003
declaring it a sin to develop a nuclear
weapon and then the CIA twice said they
don't have a nuclear weapons program.
>> So it's interesting on that question. So
the the fatwa been in place all these
years more than 20 years.
>> We're told simultaneously that Iran is a
fanatical suicidal homicidal theocracy
>> totally beyond reason. So besided are
they by their crazy religious views.
>> So there's that. But we also can't take
the fatwa seriously because it's Iran
and they lie all the time.
>> Right. But sometimes you can take things
seriously.
>> Well, but I mean it's one or the other.
Either either it's a country that issues
fatwis and takes them seriously and
therefore we should be afraid of them
because they're a theocracy or it's a
country that issues fake fatwas because
they don't really believe in the in the
idea of a fatwa. Like what is it?
>> Yeah, that's exactly right. That's an
irony I hadn't really thought of that in
all other cases, the US trumps up the
idea of thoughtwis to support their war
propaganda campaigns to launch these
wars overseas for Israel's benefit for
the benefit of military contractors,
bomb makers, the CIA, the bankers, etc.
But in the case where a fatwa was issued
as it was by Supreme Leader Ali Ham that
Iran won't have nuclear weapons, oh
that's just propaganda. They're just
saying it. It's just an inconsistency.
And that's what this whole thing has
been. This drive and push for war fervor
against Iran for three decades finally
coming to fruition. No sign it's
beneficial to us whatsoever. I'm with
Kiryaku. This is totally bending to the
will of the Israelis and specifically
the Ludnik under Netanyahu that have
wanted this war forever in the interests
of greater Israel to expand the borders
of Israel. They don't even hide this
fact as Bezel Smootrich boasts about
annexing portions of Lebanon that
beneath the Latani River and expanding
the borders of Israel. They're doing
this in Syria. They're doing this in
Lebanon. They want to do this in Gaza
against Motric calls for Israeli
settlements in Gaza. This has been on
the table for a very long time. and what
the the propagandists have have had to
do because of this. They can't always
claim that Iran was a threat to the
United States. Sometimes they do, but it
becomes more and more laughable and more
and more preposterous every time they do
that because they didn't have a delivery
system, intercontinental ballistic
missiles that could stretch the United
States. They didn't have a nuclear
weapon. But the goalpost shifts by the
propagandist to say, "Hey, they're a
threat to the United States because our
bases are in the region. They can touch
our service members. Well, why are the
bases in the region? It's to serve the
desires of Israel and Netanyahu. It
isn't to the benefit of regular
Americans. It would be better if you
shut down those bases, removed all
servicemen, brought them back home, and
again, maybe treated the military as its
original intended purpose by the
founders to defend the United States.
Imagine that. a US military, a war
department budget carved out to defend
the United States. Well, no one attacks
the United States. The United States
criminal government decided to be empire
builders long ago, mostly as a result of
the progressive era and the movement
toward, you know, exporting democracy
worldwide, which was adapted both by
neocons and neoliberals. But that
perverted the original American system.
And one of the biggest kind of junctures
in history that did this was through the
so-called Carter doctrine. Jimmy Carter
said as a matter of policy, all attacks
on US resources in the Middle East will
be perceived as attacks against the
United States in general. So that's how
they get away with selling this as a
threat to the United States. It's not a
threat to the United States the Iran
exists. It's a threat to the Israeli
perception of a threat and the idea of
American hegeimmani and American empire
in the Middle East. It's all for not.
It's all disastrous. And the US should
mind its own business for once. Our
criminal government should mind its own
business. Sever ties with Israel. Let
them do their dirty work. I don't want
to support it whatsoever. I don't want
to be complicit in their genocides, in
their wars, and all their atrocities in
the name of Epstein and the Epstein
class. But what do you guys think? Let
me know in the comments down below. Is
Kuryaku right? Is Tucker Carlson right
about this? What is it about Israel that
hijacked our foreign policy? Was there
any time in which this happened? Was it
since the inception of Israel, since '
67,73?
Any time after that? When do you think
it really took root? And is Trump the
most radically Zionist president ever? I
think so. What do you think? Let me know
in the comments down below. Like the
video, subscribe to the channel. Also,
subscribe to Tucker. Great guest. Love
Kiryaku. Generally agree with him. Only
a few things that I would have issue
with here as I stated, but I really like
him as a guest. Would love to get him on
this show too in the future. And if you
like this video and breakdown, please
consider joining as a YouTube member.
You can join me on Liberty Vault by
clicking the join button down below.
Doing that gets you immediate access to
all my videos as a member and I really
appreciate your support for that. And
also, if you want a free copy of my
first book, Compact of the Republic,
click the link in the description down
below. That'll send you out to a
website. You just plug in your email
right there and I'll send you a full
free copy of that book. No obligations
whatsoever. And I have some serious
serious demands for this criminal
Epstein class corrupt Israel first war
regime. And I won't apologize for him.
No more war. No more debt, no more
inflation, and no more empire. Peace
out, guys.